Ásgeir Berg Matthíasson

asgeirberg@hi.is https://asgeirberg.org

Research interests

My current research project, which is funded by the *Icelandic Research Fund* (RANNÍS), is to develop a conventionalist account of mathematical truth, based on my previous work on the rule-following paradox and Wittgenstein's philosophy of mathematics.

Areas of Specialisation: Wittgenstein, philosophy of mathematics, philosophy of logic, the rule-following paradox.

Areas of Competence: Metaphysics, logic, epistemology, history of analytic philosophy.

Current position

2022 — present Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Institute of Philosophy, University of Iceland

Previous positions

2021 — 2022 **Adjunct Lecturer** University of Iceland

2020 — 2021 Sessional Instructor University of Iceland

2016 — 2019 Early Stage Researcher University of Stirling

Education

2020 **PhD in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)
2015 **M.Litt. in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

2013 **M.Sc. in Logic**, University of Amsterdam

Publications

Peer-reviewed journal articles 2024 J4 Wittgenstein on Mathematical Facts Philosophical Investigations J3 Was Wittgenstein a Radical Conventionalist? Synthese 203 (37) 2022 J2 Rules as constitutive practices defined by correlated equilibria Inquiry 65: 1-35 2021 J1 Contradictions and falling bridges: what was Wittgenstein's reply to Turing? British Journal for History of Philosophy 29 (3): 537-559 Other publications 2024 J3 Rannsóknir í heimspeki: Ritdómur Hugur: tímarit um heimspeki 2022 J2 fyrir öll x Icelandic version of forall x, an open and free logic textbook 2017 J1 Af aðferð Chomskys og vinnubrögðum Guðna Elíssonar Ritið: tímarit Hugvísindastofnunar Selected talks 2024 T14 Family-resemblance concepts and Wittgenstein's metaphilosophy, Young Network for Wittgensteinian Philosophy Colloquium, Brussels T13 Was Wittgenstein a Radical Conventionalist?, Wittgenstein and the formal sciences 3, World Logic Day 2023 T12 What is it to Follow a Rule?, Institute of Philosophy, University of Iceland, Reykjavík T11 Philosophical Implications of Using Large Language Models in Mathematics, Philosophy of Mathematics Seminar, University of Oxford, Oxford (with Fenner Tanswell) T10 Was Wittgenstein a Radical Conventionalist?, Wittgenstein and the Philosophy of Mathematical Practice, Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Brussels 2022 T09 Wittgenstein on contradiction: Wittgenstein's debate with Turing, 11th British Wittgenstein Society Conference: Wittgenstein and Al, New College of the Humanities, London 2019 T08 What was Wittgenstein's reply to Turing?: Contradictions and falling bridges, Wittgenstein: Naturalism and Necessity, University of Bergen, Bergen T07 A Game-Theoretic Solution to the Rule-Following Paradox, Arché 20th Anniversary Conference, University of St Andrews, St Andrews